So there's this dating app I've started using.
我最近開始用一個交友應用程式
A dating app?
交友應用程式？
I signed up after a friend got me onto it
有個朋友推薦，我就註冊了
and I am obsessed!
現在完全沉迷其中
FIND THE ONE - DATING APP
（速配，找到對的人）
That's the one where girls can use a nickname and get to sign up for free?
就是女性可以使用暱稱 免費註冊的那個嗎？
They say PairPair has a lot of guys who own real estate.
聽說“速配”上有很多有房有地的男人
Real estate?
有房有地？
It has got guys in their 30s with luxury apartments
比如三十多歲就擁有豪華公寓的男人
and celebrity-types set to inherit the family property.
還有準備繼承家族產業的名人
-Wow! Sign me up. -You see?
-哇，幫我也註冊一下 -很棒吧？
-Where is it? -Yeah, give it a go.
-在哪裡？ -試試看吧
You go to the App Store and download PairPair.
先進入應用商店下載“速配”
-Yep. -Click "Start."
-好 -按一下“開始”
FIND THE ONE - START
速配，找到對的人，開始）
-Female.
-選擇“女性” -女性
And your nickname?
妳的暱稱是什麼？
Do people use their real info?
人們會使用自己真實的資訊嗎？
ENTER YOUR NICKNAME - YOKO
（輸入暱稱，洋子）
Who knows?
誰知道呢？
They don't?
難道不會嗎？
I don't know. Maybe?
我也不知道，很難說
YOKO - NON-SMOKER
（洋子，158公分，不抽菸）
-What about you? -I use my real info.
-你呢？ -我會用真實的資訊
-Really? -Yeah, I put my real name, Yui.
-真的嗎？ -對，我用了真名，結衣
REGISTRATION COMPLETE
（註冊完成）
-It's time. Let's go. -What?
-時間到了，走吧 -什麼？
But we were just getting started!
但是我們才剛開始呢
Come on. Before we get in trouble.
快點，不然會有麻煩
WATAYAN - 35YO - TOKYO SALARY 7 MILLION
（綿村，35歲，170公分 東京，年薪七百萬）
ABOUT ME - LOOKING TO BUY A HOUSE IN MY THIRTIES!
（自我介紹，三十多歲，打算買房）
LIKE
（喜歡）
Mr. Tosaka!
社長
We've been very active lately.
同仁們最近非常活躍
Kurosu is steadily pulling new contracts on full commission.
自由仲介黑須一直穩定地帶來合約
You have a good eye!
你的眼光真好
Fujiwara's been using his connections and continues to get great results.
藤原也用他的人脈持續產出著好結果
Thank you for doing business with me today.
感謝你今天的選擇
Even Tokage's managed to finalize two properties!
就連十影也完成了兩筆業務
So Tokage was a good catalyst for helping Nagase and Tsukishita out of their slump.
看來十影是個不錯的催化劑 幫助永瀨和月下走出了低谷
Mr. Nagase?
永瀨前輩？
There you are.
終於找到你了
Mr. Okawa's looking for you.
大河部長在找你
I've gotta make a personal call.
我出來打一通私人電話
Could it be--
難道是…
A little love call to Miss Enomoto?
打給榎本小姐說情話？
What?
什麼？
Remember before?
之前不是…
Will you
你能不能…
be my fiancé?
做我的未婚夫？
Miss Enomoto professed her love for you!
榎本小姐向你表明了愛意
And you've been dating ever since, right?
後來你們就交往了，對吧？
Not exactly.
並沒有
My gran from Akita is trying to set me up with a husband.
我的奶奶住在秋田 她想幫我安排一個丈夫
She can be very pushy, so it was an accident.
她有時挺強勢的，所以事出突然…
I told a little white lie saying I'd found a potential husband.
我對她撒了個善意的小謊 說我已經有丈夫人選了
I see.
原來如此
She asked me what he was like,
她問我對方長什麼樣子
and all I could think of were qualities that you had!
我當時只能想到永瀨你的各種特徵
-What? -Please?
-什麼？ -拜託了？
She wants you to pretend?
她想讓你假扮？
Her grandma's coming down from Akita at 1:00 p.m. on Saturday.
她奶奶週六下午一點會從秋田過來
Miss Enomoto's going to pick her up, then wants us to all go for lunch.
她先去接她 然後希望我們一起吃個午飯
But I've thought about it.
但是我考慮過了
If I cannot tell a lie, how can I possibly pretend to be her boyfriend?
既然我無法說謊 又怎能假裝是她的男友呢？
I'm gonna refuse.
我要拒絕她
You can't!
不行
She immediately thought of you when asked who her boyfriend was.
她被奶奶問到男友是誰 第一個想到的人就是你
That means she really must like you!
說明她果然是喜歡永瀨前輩的
You'll be fine.
沒關係的
I'll go with you as back up to make sure you don't put your foot in your mouth.
我當你的後援，確保你不會亂說話
MINERVA REAL ESTATE
（密涅瓦不動產）
Yes, thank you.
對，非常感謝
In that case, I'll get the contract ready.
既然如此，我會準備好合約
Yes, goodbye.
好的，再見
Kamiki, you sold another studio apartment as an investment?
神木先生，你又賣出了一間 一房投資公寓嗎？
You sold the land for the shopping district and found the perfect tenants.
你賣出了商店街的土地 還找到了理想的房客
You've got that lead position at the new Tachikawa store in the bag!
立川新店的店長之位非你莫屬了
Mr. Ikaruga said he'd give it to whoever comes in first this month.
社長說會交給這個月的業務冠軍
Hello, Mr. Watamura.
綿村先生，你好
Do you think we could meet in person?
要不要見個面？
EP 7 OF 10 FORBIDDEN FRUIT
第7集：禁忌之果
Not her.
不是她
Sorry to do this last minute. I'm suddenly not feeling too well.
抱歉現在才跟你說，我突然不太舒服
Yoko…
洋子小姐
And here I thought we'd finally get to meet.
我還以為我們終於能見面了呢
-Excuse me. -Yes?
-打擾了 -什麼事？
Are you Mr. Watamura?
請問你是綿村先生嗎？
Yes, and you are?
對，妳是哪位？
I'm Yoko's friend. My name is Ryoko Hanasawa.
我是洋子的朋友，我叫花澤涼子
-Ms. Hanasawa? -Yes.
-花澤小姐？ -對
Yoko said she was having a first date with a potential marriage partner,
洋子說她原本要跟人初次約會 對方是可能結婚的對象
and she asked me to come along to help keep the conversation flowing.
她讓我過來幫忙，確保溝通順暢
Really?
這樣嗎？
Yes.
對
It's too bad she just texted me.
不過洋子剛才傳簡訊說不來了
What?
什麼？
HIROSHI WATAMURA SYSTEMS ENGINEER
（綿村博士，系統工程師）
Wow, so you work for TTN Data.
原來綿村先生在TTN數據公司工作啊
HIROSHI WATAMURA TTN DATA SYSTEMS ENGINEER
（綿村博士，TTN數據系統工程師）
Yes.
對
Systems development. So that must mean you're a programmer?
做系統開發 那你一定是程式設計師吧？
I'll bet you work on systems for the government and big businesses.
我猜你一定是 為政府和大企業做系統的
Yeah, I guess.
算是吧
I'm glad I met you.
見到你我就放心了
What?
什麼？
Yoko's always been passionate about finding a husband.
洋子一直很想結婚
I'm glad she found someone like you.
如果是綿村先生這樣的人 就能讓人放心了
-You really mean that? -Yes.
-真的嗎？ -是的
She used to always talk about how excited she was to get married
她成天說真的很期待結婚
and live in a beautiful house with her new husband.
期待跟新婚丈夫一起 住在美麗的房子裡
I see.
這樣啊
I actually messaged her saying,
其實我傳過訊息給她
"Now that I'm in my 30s I was thinking of buying a place,"
我現在三十多歲了，在考慮買房子
and she replied saying she liked the idea.
她回覆說很喜歡我這個想法
I totally agree.
我完全同意
I always say that rent money is dead money.
我總是說花錢租房太浪費了
I think it's great that you want to buy.
我覺得你想買房真是太好了
Yoko said the same thing!
洋子小姐也是這麼說的
I have 10 million saved up so far.
我目前有一千萬存款
That reminds me!
對了
I'm actually in this line of work.
我其實就是從事這一行
You're a realtor?
妳是不動產仲介？
Just between the two of us,
我偷偷告訴你吧
there's a place nearby that Yoko said she always wanted to live in
附近有個地方，洋子說她一直希望
once she got married.
婚後能住在那裡
Really?
真的嗎？
Want to have a peek?
要不要去看看？
Yes, please!
好的，拜託了
Thank you for the meal.
謝謝你的招待
-It's fine. -Thank you so much.
-不必客氣 -非常感謝
Shall I call a taxi?
我叫個計程車吧？
No, we can walk there.
不用，我們可以走路過去
The high-rise building is relatively new…
那棟摩天大樓相對較新…
HEAVENLY CREST YAOKI 69.8 MILLION YEN
（八起天廈，6980萬）
…and it's priced below market value.
…而且低於市場價
-Why's that? -Why is it cheap?
-為什麼？ -你是說便宜的理由嗎？
Well, you see--
理由是…
It's because people are saying it's defective.
因為大家都說那裡有缺陷
What?
什麼？
It may be cheap, but it's definitely not a bargain.
可能看似便宜，但是便宜沒好貨
Are you kidding me?
你在耍我嗎？
That's our honest realtor.
果然是我們的正直仲介
Yeah, I know.
我知道
Is this the defective one?
這就是有缺陷的那棟樓嗎？
Yeah, they say it's not even resistant to earthquakes.
對，聽說無法抗震
Thanks. Got it.
謝謝，了解
-Mr. Nagase. -Yeah?
-永瀨 -什麼事？
There's an old lady at reception.
櫃檯有一位老婆婆
An old lady? What does she want?
老婆婆？要幹什麼？
She wants to buy a high-rise outright with cash.
她想直接用現金買摩天大樓公寓
-A high-rise? -Yes.
-摩天大樓？ -對
Outright with cash?
直接用現金？
-Bring her through now. -Yes.
-快把人帶進來 -好
-Get the files. -On it.
-去準備資料 -明白
-Let's go. -Okay.
-走吧 -好
That's right.
沒錯
My little girl has finally found herself a husband in Tokyo!
我的寶貝孫女 總算在東京找到了如意郎君
This will be a gift.
這是我送給他們的禮物
How exciting.
原來如此
HIGH-RISE PURCHASE CONSULTATION
（摩天大樓買房諮詢）
Congratulations.
真是恭喜了
But you see, I'm too old to take out a loan.
不過我年紀太大，不能申請貸款
This is everything I've managed to scrape up for my little girl.
這些就是我省吃儉用 為寶貝孫女存下的一切
These are my life savings.
是我這輩子的積蓄
Let's have a look.
請讓我看看
Thank you.
謝謝
One zero, two zeros--
個、十…
-200 million? -No.
-兩億？ -不
Calm down. It's 20 million.
別激動，是兩千萬
20 million?
兩千萬啊？
-Here. Thank you. -Sorry.
-還給你，謝謝 -失禮了
What do you think?
你怎麼想？
Is it enough
夠不夠
to buy a high-rise?
買摩天大樓的公寓？
Inner city high-rises can go anywhere from 50 to 200 million yen.
市區摩天大樓的房價 通常在五千萬到兩億不等
The more expensive ones can even go for 5.5 billion yen.
再貴一點的甚至能達到55億
I'd love to help you, but--
我也很想幫你，但是…
High-rises ain't no playground.
摩天大樓可不是公共遊樂場
Only true winners in life get to live in a high-rise in Tokyo.
只有真正的人生贏家 才能住進東京的摩天大樓
Land in Tokyo is incredibly expensive.
東京寸土寸金
You want to buy a high-rise as a present?
婆婆，妳想買摩天大樓給人當禮物？
The day you realize that's impossible is the day you'll get your elder wisdom!
趕緊認清現實吧，這是不可能的
Mr. Nagase, you don't have to say it like that!
永瀨前輩，沒必要說得那麼直白
Why don't you give them some financial assistance
不如等他們自己買房時
when they eventually go to buy their own property instead?
妳提供些經濟支援吧？
There are plenty of previously-owned properties in the 20 million range.
有不少兩千萬左右的中古屋
Like this, for example.
例如這間
Does it really matter if it's not a high-rise?
摩天大樓真的很重要嗎？
Looks like I've just been a bother.
看來我給各位添麻煩了
I hope you'll forgive me.
請原諒
Goodbye.
再會
"Goodbye"?
“再會”？
MORIARTY NISHI-OGIKUBO APARTMENT
（莫里亞提西荻窪公寓）
What do you think?
你覺得如何？
Well…
這…
Did Yoko really say she wanted to live here?
洋子小姐真的說她想住在這裡嗎？
Why do you say that?
為什麼這麼問？
Well, it's just a lot more basic than I thought it would be.
只是這裡比我想像中簡單太多了
Yoko's just a really economical kinda gal!
洋子是個很看重經濟實惠的女孩
I see.
這樣啊
How much was it going for, by the way?
對了，這間要價多少？
50 million.
五千萬
With a deposit of five million yen,
訂金五百萬
the remaining 45 million can be paid off on a 35-year loan,
剩下的4500萬可以申請35年的貸款
leaving you with a monthly repayment of 110,000 yen.
也就是每月只需還款11萬
Wow, that's cheaper than what I'm paying now in rent.
那比我現在的房租還便宜
You see? Economical.
我就說吧，經濟實惠
Would you consider buying it?
你會考慮買下嗎？
You could buy it as a surprise gift for Yoko!
這間公寓可以當做你給洋子的驚喜
I'm sure she'd be delighted.
她一定會非常開心
That's a good idea!
好主意
Can I take some photos?
我能拍些照片嗎？
Of course!
當然可以
Here's the contract.
這是合約
PURCHASE AND SALE AGREEMENT OF REAL ESTATE
（不動產買賣合約）
There's just one thing.
其實…有個小問題
Yes?
請說
I…
其實我…
Actually, I can't get the five million for the deposit.
我拿不出五百萬訂金
Sorry?
什麼？
So we can't do the contract without the deposit, can we?
不付訂金就無法簽合約吧？
I guess not…
應該不行
TOSAKA REAL ESTATE NO.1 IN THE AREA
（登坂不動產，本區第一）
TEN MINS. ON FOOT TO KOKUBUNJI STATION 60 MILLION YEN
（步行十分鐘可達國分寺站 六千萬元）
PROPERTY PURCHASE CONSULTATION
（購屋諮詢）
Please wait here.
請稍坐片刻
-It's being used as a study. -I see.
-這裡是書房 -這樣啊
Is that someone who wants to buy a property?
那個人想買房子嗎？
Yeah, a previously-owned condo near Kokubunji.
對，想買國分寺附近的中古公寓
That sounds great!
太好了
It's not.
才不好
He wants us to foot the deposit
他要我們墊付訂金
and says he'll pay us back later.
以後再還給我們
That would be inducement, right?
那樣算是合約誘導吧？
Exactly.
沒錯
What's inducement?
什麼是合約誘導？
Let's break it down.
我來解釋一下
If a realtor tells someone they'll lend them the money for a deposit,
如果仲介告知客戶 可以借款幫其墊付訂金
telling them they can pay it back later or in installments,
並稱客戶可以稍後還款或分期償還
the realtor is rushing the sale and inducing the client into a contract.
那這名仲介就是為了促成交易 在誘導客戶簽合約
This is a violation of real estate law.
這將違反不動產法
The penalty is a maximum six months in prison,
最高將面臨六個月刑期
a fine of up to one million yen,
或一百萬以下的罰款
or even both.
也可能兩者並罰
Your business will be suspended,
該仲介所在公司將被勒令停業
and you may even be penalized by losing your realtor's license.
其本人甚至可能 被吊銷不動產經紀人執照
Oh no!
不
And so, realtors should steer clear of inducement.
因此，仲介應避免誘導
Don't do it!
絕對不行
Ms. Hanasawa.
花澤女士
You're certainly working hard.
妳工作可真努力啊
But don't work too hard.
但是別太努力
You should be proud to come in second.
妳應該為得到第二名而自豪
After all, coming in second means you're top of the losers.
畢竟，第二名相當於失敗者中的第一
Mr. Ikaruga, I'd like your advice.
社長，我想聽聽你的建議
It's a personal request.
這是個私人請求
TTN DATA - TOKYO HEADQUARTERS
（TTN數據，東京總部）
Mr. Watamura, I managed to find the five million for you.
綿村先生 我想辦法幫你湊到了五百萬
You did?
真的嗎？
You can pay me back later.
你可以稍後還我
Thank you so much! You're a big help.
太感謝了，妳真是幫了大忙
But keep this to yourself.
不過，這事只能你知我知
And I'll keep it a secret from Yoko.
我也會在洋子面前保密
Of course.
當然
I'm afraid Tosaka Real Estate is unable to pay the deposit on your behalf.
恐怕登坂不動產無法幫你墊付訂金
Come on. Help a man out here.
拜託，幫幫兄弟嘛
We finally found the perfect place.
我們好不容易找到了理想的房子
AKIHIRO DOI 47 YO - RESTAURATEUR
（土井秋廣，47歲，餐廳老闆）
You got quotas, right?
你有業績目標吧？
I'll bet they're hard to fill.
一定很難完成吧？
It's not a bad deal for you.
這筆生意對你來說並不吃虧
I'm afraid it's illegal, so…
恐怕這會違反法律，所以…
Listen here, Mr. Banknote.
聽好了，諭吉臉
Yes, our clients' faces totally look like the guy on the 10,000-yen note.
沒錯，這位顧客長得就像 萬元紙幣上的福澤諭吉
FUKUZAWA YUKICHI
（福澤諭吉）
Yukichi!
諭吉
I am practically champing at the bit to help you.
我其實迫不及待地想幫你
However…
但是
I want to do my job with my head held high.
我想堂堂正正地做事
Do you know why inducement is against the law?
你知道合約誘導為何是違法行為嗎？
Inducement?
合約誘導？
Buying a property is one of the biggest decisions most people will ever make,
買房是大部分人一輩子最大的決定
and us realtors take a small brokerage fee once the contract has been concluded.
一旦簽訂合約 我們仲介就能從中賺取小額仲介費
Yeah?
是的
But some realtors get greedy and try to push sales onto clients who aren't ready.
然而，有些仲介貪得無厭 會催促還沒準備好的客戶儘快交易
What do you think happens if they foot the deposit and rush to a sale?
你覺得要是讓他們墊付訂金 草草簽訂合約，結果會如何？
If you rush this decision to buy your forever home,
這是你要住一輩子的房子 如果草率決定
won't you regret it later?
你日後不會後悔嗎？
I want my clients to be absolutely happy with their purchase.
我希望自己的客戶 對買下的房子絕對滿意
So even if it were legal,
所以就算這麼做不違法
I would never induce my clients into contract.
我也絕不會誘導我的客戶簽合約
Sorry you had to call.
抱歉給妳添麻煩了
Ms. Hanasawa.
花澤女士
He got into a fight with his friend and he fell over after being pushed.
他跟小朋友打起來了 對方推他，他就摔倒了
Hokuto wasn't doing anything wrong.
北斗完全沒做錯什麼
MIREI FUJIMORI CHILDCARE WORKER
（藤森美玲，幼教師）
The rule is everyone has to share the scooter and we get five minutes each,
規則是大家輪流玩滑板車 每人五分鐘
and one of the kids wouldn't share.
但有個孩子不肯跟人分享
Hokuto was very brave and spoke up to the child.
北斗非常勇敢地跟他理論
That's when it turned into an argument.
然後兩人就打起來了
Mama.
媽媽
I was right, wasn't I?
我沒做錯事吧？
You have to follow the rules.
要遵守規則
That's what you always say.
媽媽總是這麼說
NEW FIXED INTEREST RATE HOME LOAN PLAN
（全新推出，固定利率住宅貸款）
Tomorrow's the big day, right?
明天是美波的大日子吧？
When Mr. Nagase gets to meet the grandparents.
永瀨先生要跟妳奶奶見面了
It's not that formal.
也沒那麼正式
He's only pretending to be my boyfriend.
他只是假扮我的男友
Isn't this just the next step to actually dating?
接下來不就是要真正約會嗎？
Absolutely no way!
絕對不可能
No way. Not at all.
絕對不會，絕對
No way. Way?
絕對不會，絕對嗎？
No way. Way? Way?
絕對不可能嗎？還是有可能？
Way means way.
絕對有可能
Way?
是嗎？
Open up.
打開了
Hello, ma'am.
妳好
I'm from Tosaka Real Estate.
我是登坂不動產的員工
I see.
是妳啊
Sorry about the other day.
那天真是抱歉
Sorry we couldn't help you with the high-rise.
我們沒能幫妳在摩天大樓買房子
It's quite all right.
沒關係
Would you like to have a bite?
妳要嚐嚐嗎？
-Thank you. -Go on.
-我開動了 -吃吧
That's so good!
真好吃
-Right? -Yes.
-真的嗎？ -真的
I'm hungry. How about you?
我餓了，你呢？
I'm not.
我一點也不餓
-That's so good! -Sure is.
-太好吃了 -當然
Miss Tsukishita!
月下姐姐
Hokuto! Did you just finish preschool?
北斗，幼稚園放學了嗎？
Yeah.
對
Ms. Hanasawa.
花澤女士
Mama!
媽媽
I see you.
我看到你了
Ms. Hanasawa and I are fated rivals.
花澤女士是我的冤家對頭
-You are? -Right, Ms. Hanasawa?
-是嗎？ -花澤，對不對？
We're just in the same industry.
我們只是同業而已
So you're a realtor too?
妳也是不動產仲介嗎？
Yes, that's right.
沒錯
My name is Ryoko Hanasawa.
我叫花澤涼子
Thank you.
謝謝
She's got a sharp tongue, goes against the grain, and is completely overbearing.
她這個人牙尖嘴利 不按牌理出牌，而且盛氣凌人
Now look here--
喂…
But she always has the customer's best interests at heart.
不過呢，她也始終 把客人的利益放在心上
You can trust Ms. Hanasawa.
妳可以信任花澤女士
What's this all of a sudden? You'll make me blush.
怎麼突然這麼說？我都臉紅了
What a great time to be alive.
真是個美好的時代啊
Two women, marching out into the world,
兩位女性走入社會
doing a bang-up job.
做著了不起的工作
What a wonderful thing!
真是太好了
You must have worked real hard to get where you are today.
妳一定非常努力才有今天的成就
Your face says it all.
從妳臉上看得出來
Well…
這…
I…
我…
If I ever become the boss,
如果有機會自己開公司
I want to set up a day-care center in the workplace.
我想在公司裡設立托兒所
Day-care center?
托兒所？
I want to set aside a kids' room
我想留出一些空間給孩子們
and I want changing tables in all the men's bathrooms.
還想讓男廁裡都有尿布更換臺
So men can take care of their children while they're at work?
這樣男人就能邊工作邊照顧孩子？
I'll offer both maternity and paternity leave.
我會提供產假和陪產假
I want to create a workplace that's comfortable for everyone.
我想創造一個人人都待得舒適的職場
That sounds amazing!
聽起來太棒了
I had no idea you had such lofty ambitions.
我真不知道花澤妳有這麼遠大的抱負
Please let me know if there's anything I can do to help.
如果有什麼我能幫忙的 請一定要告訴我
I want to help you.
我想幫妳
Go for it!
加油啊
I think I just gained two more granddaughters!
我好像剛收穫了兩個孫女
Grandma's got your back.
奶奶支持妳們
HELPING YOU FIND A HOME
（協助你找到新家）
Today's the big day, Mr. Nagase.
永瀨前輩，今天就是大日子了
What?
什麼？
Don't tell me you've forgotten about your big day?
你不會忘了今天是你的大日子吧？
You're meeting up with Miss Enomoto and her grandmother at 1:00.
下午一點 你要跟榎本小姐和她奶奶見面
That's right. Man, I so don't wanna go.
對哦，真是的，我真不想去
Pull yourself together, man!
拜託，振作點
Mr. Nagase.
永瀨
That Mr. Doi from yesterday is here to see you again.
昨天來過的土井先生又來找你了
What? Seriously?
什麼？不會吧
The deposit.
訂金
I got it for you.
我拿來了
I cooled down after our meeting,
昨天見面後，我冷靜下來
and I thought long and hard about whether I really needed this place.
認真考慮了很久 我是否真的需要這間房子
And I realized
我發現
I absolutely must have it.
我無論如何都想擁有它
My family will be happy here
我的家人能在這裡幸福地生活
and it'll be good for my work.
對我的工作也有好處
So I sold the motorbike.
所以我賣了摩托車
I said to the wife I'm happy to have less spending money,
我跟老婆說，很高興以後能少花點錢
and even her parents couldn't help but to help us out.
就連她父母也主動幫忙我們
So that's how you got the money.
原來這錢是這麼來的
I'd kind of assumed something else.
我以為是別的方法
What did you assume?
妳以為是怎樣？
-No-- -Like you broke thumbs to get it.
-沒有… -例如你恐嚇敲詐別人
-What? -No! I didn't mean that!
-什麼？ -不，我不是那個意思
-That's not it. -Look at him.
-才不是 -瞧他的樣子
-I didn't-- -In any case,
-我沒… -總而言之
let's proceed with the purchase.
我們繼續談買房子的流程吧
-Yes. -Sure.
-沒錯 -是的
WE'LL HELP YOU FIND THE PERFECT HIGH-RISE - MINERVA
（我們將協助你 找到理想的摩天大樓，密涅瓦）
We'll be in touch with you again.
我們會再聯絡你
-Yes, please. -Goodbye.
-拜託了 -再會
Excuse me?
打擾了
Is Ms. Hanasawa around?
請問花澤女士在嗎？
Ms. Hanasawa? She's out at the moment.
花澤女士嗎？她出去了
I see. I'll come back later.
這樣啊，那我晚點再來
Goodbye.
再會
I can help if you like, ma'am.
婆婆，讓我來幫妳吧
No thank you, dear--
不用了，謝謝…
Higashino.
東野
What happened? Why did you withdraw from our contract?
怎麼回事？ 你為何要取消我們的合約？
I'm sorry.
很抱歉
My job got reassigned out of the blue.
我突然被調職了
They suddenly want me in Kansai.
他們突然要調我去關西
I can't very well be setting up my life in Tokyo now, can I?
我現在不能在東京置產了
There's no point in complaining about it.
向公司投訴也沒用
And Yoko's been ghosting me lately.
而且洋子小姐最近也不理我
We still haven't even met in person.
我們甚至還沒見過面
I'm beginning to wonder if maybe I was just coming on too strong.
我在想，是不是我太強勢了
Sorry.
抱歉
I know you tried to help.
我知道妳盡力幫我了
Wait.
等等
I'm actually considering buying a studio apartment for investment purposes.
其實我在考慮 乾脆買間一房公寓來投資
That way I can transfer for work--
這樣我就可以放心調去工作
Are you sure?
你確定嗎？
If you cancel now, it'll be at the buyer's discretion
如果現在取消，那就是買方違約
and you may not get your deposit back.
你的訂金可能就要不回來了
You mean the deposit your company paid for?
妳是說妳幫忙墊付的訂金嗎？
Yes!
對
What's that got to do with me?
那跟我有什麼關係？
What?
什麼？
You paying for my deposit was an inducement to enter into a contract.
妳幫我墊付訂金是合約誘導
It's a violation of real estate law.
違反了不動產法
The guy who recommended I get a studio apartment said so.
推薦我買一房公寓的人是這麼說的
I am under no obligation to pay back that deposit.
我沒有義務償還那筆訂金
If you try to say otherwise,
如果妳還有異議
I'll raise it with the Office for Housing Policy.
我會向住房政策辦公室檢舉
Minerva Real Estate will get a suspension.
密涅瓦不動產會被勒令停業
Apparently, you could even lose your realtor's license.
妳甚至可能被吊銷不動產經紀人執照
That five million we paid for Mr. Watamura has already gone to the seller.
我們幫綿村墊付的五百萬 已經轉帳給賣家了
Thank you.
謝謝
Kamiki, I made the reservation.
神木先生，我訂好了
He's a big player at a large IT firm.
他是大型科技公司的大人物
I want this to be perfect.
一定要萬無一失
Yes, sir.
是
Is it another contract?
又有一份合約了嗎？
No, he helped me transfer a thorn in my side to Kansai.
不，他幫我把一個眼中釘調到了關西
That guy you sold an Osakan investment property to?
就是跟你買了 大阪投資公寓的那位嗎？
Watamura, right? That bumbling paper pusher?
叫綿村吧？那個不重要的小人物？
That's the one.
對
So it was you pulling the strings.
原來是你在背後搞鬼
You told him to cancel my contract
你叫他取消跟我的合約
so you could push your own property on him.
這樣就能讓他買下你手裡的房子
How could you stoop so low?
你怎麼能如此沒有底線？
I told you to be proud of being second.
我說過，妳該為得到第二名而自豪
Mr. Nagase, your tie is crooked.
永瀨前輩，你的領帶歪了
-Thanks. -There you go.
-謝謝 -好了
Aren't you being a little too nervous?
你是不是有點緊張過頭了？
You'll be fine.
沒事的
-Nagase! -Miss Enomoto?
-永瀨 -榎本小姐？
What's wrong? I thought you'd be at Tokyo Station--
怎麼了？妳不是去東京站…
I just got a call from Gran saying she can't make it to the station!
我剛接到奶奶的電話 她說不能去車站了
-What? -Why?
-什麼？ -為什麼？
It seems she's been staying with relatives for the past two days.
她這兩天好像一直住在親戚家
She said she'd call later today after her errands but now she's not picking up!
她說今天辦完事會打給我 但是她現在根本不接電話了
It's okay. Calm down.
沒事的，別著急
Let's just find the store she might have stopped in at.
我們先找找她可能去的地方
-Okay. -Do you have a photo?
-好 -你有她的照片嗎？
Yes.
有
Here.
這裡
Is it enough
夠不夠
to buy a high-rise?
買摩天大樓的公寓？
No way.
不會吧
Wait.
什麼？
She came to see us just the other day.
她前幾天來找過我們
She wanted to buy a high-rise as a present for her granddaughter.
她想買摩天大樓的公寓給孫女當禮物
So that was you!
原來就是美波小姐妳
That reminds me.
說起來
Gran used to always say when I was a little girl…
我小的時候，奶奶總是說
When you get married, Minami,
等我們美波結婚的時候
Gran's gonna help you and your future husband.
奶奶一定會幫忙妳和未來的丈夫
She's gonna buy you your very own house to live in.
我會給你們屬於自己的房子
Thanks!
好
So,
這麼說來
does that mean your future husband…
妳的未來丈夫就是…
Well, I'll be darned!
哇，太棒了
What do you think, Mrs. Enomoto?
榎本婆婆覺得怎麼樣？
How's the window view
豪華摩天大樓，八起天廈的窗景
in the luxurious high-rise that is Heavenly Crest Yaoki?
妳滿意嗎？
Window view?
窗景？
My apologies.
抱歉
My stars!
天啊
You really can see everything!
真是一覽無遺啊
Feels like I'm in a Ferris wheel!
我就像在摩天輪上一樣
That's the feeling one can only get from living in a high-rise.
這種感覺只有住在摩天大樓才能體會
A place like this
這樣的房子
would make my granddaughter and her future husband so happy!
一定能讓我孫女 和她未來的丈夫無比幸福
You're absolutely right!
那是當然的
Want to purchase?
要買摩天大樓嗎？
That old lady from Akita really likes her high-rises.
秋田來的老婆婆 非常喜歡那棟摩天大樓的房子
Doesn't look like she's made of money.
看不出來她那麼有錢
I had no idea at first as to why Kamiki was so adamant about pursuing her.
我一開始還想不通 神木先生為什麼那麼執著地爭取她
Please prepare a meeting room.
請準備一間會客室
I took a look at her assets,
我查了一下她的資產
and guess how much her land in Akita is worth?
猜猜她在秋田的土地值多少錢？
Still,
不過呢
I'll bet it costs around 5.5 billion.
這肯定得花55億吧
It's not that much.
不用那麼多
It's 80 million.
只要八千萬
HEAVENLY CREST YAOKI 80 MILLION YEN
（八起天廈，八千萬元）
No, it's not for me.
那我也買不起
I only have 20 million.
我只有兩千萬
Don't worry.
不必擔心
I know there are plans to develop a large-scale project
我知道妳現在居住的秋田內海町附近
near your current residence in Utsumi Town in Akita.
有開發大型項目的計劃
Have you ever received any queries
最近可曾有人找過妳
about selling your house and your farmland?
詢問出售房屋和農田的事？
I have.
確實有
By my estimates,
據我估計
you'd get at least 60 million yen for the land.
妳的土地至少能賣六千萬
Combine that with your 20 million…
加上妳手裡的兩千萬…
TOTAL 80 MILLION YEN
（總計八千萬）
…and you can buy the high-rise.
…就能買下摩天大樓的房子了
I suppose I could sell my land in Akita.
我應該可以賣掉秋田的土地
Mr. Nagase!
永瀨前輩
I got us a taxi.
我叫到計程車了
Okay.
好
Let's visit all the real estate agencies she could have gone to.
我們先去她可能去過的不動產公司
MS. HANASAWA MINERVA REAL ESTATE
（花澤女士，密涅瓦不動產）
-Mrs. Enomoto. -Gran!
-榎本婆婆 -奶奶
Wait. What are you doing?
等等，你們要做什麼？
We'll call the police.
我們要報警了
This way.
這邊
She's from Akita, and she's looking to purchase a high-rise.
她來自秋田，想買摩天大樓的公寓
I thought it might be her.
我覺得可能是她
-Right. -Gran!
-好了 -奶奶
Gran!
奶奶
Minami?
美波？
Kamiki?
神木先生？
Thank you for before.
之前的事很謝謝妳
Mr. Kamiki, are you trying to trick Mrs. Enomoto now?
神木先生 你現在又想騙榎本婆婆嗎？
How very rude of you.
妳也太失禮了
I'm merely assisting Mrs. Enomoto to purchase a high-rise
我只是在幫助榎本婆婆 給她的寶貝孫女
for her beloved granddaughter.
買摩天大樓的房子
Minami.
美波
Remember the promise I made when you were a little one?
記得妳小時候我答應過的事嗎？
When my beautiful little Minami becomes a bride,
等我漂亮的美波寶貝成為新娘
Grandma's dream is to buy you your own house to live in!
奶奶的夢想 就是買一間屬於妳自己的房子
It is nothing short of enviable.
真是太令人羨慕了
We at Minerva are always happy to help our clients find happiness in their homes.
我們密涅瓦不動產 隨時樂意幫助客戶找到幸福的家
That's rich.
真不要臉
Mrs. Enomoto, I know you want to take care of your granddaughter.
婆婆，我知道妳想照顧孫女
I'm sure her future husband would also--
我相信她未來的丈夫也一定…
No, I don't know about him, but have you ever heard of an "unsolicited favor"?
我不知道他怎麼樣，但妳可知道 有個說法叫“不請自來的恩惠”
Did you even ask what she wants?
妳有沒有問過她的意願？
Does she even want a high-rise?
她真的想要摩天大樓的房子嗎？
What's most important in real estate
關於房子，最重要的是
are the dreams and the life plans of the people who will live there.
將要住進其中的人 他們的夢想和人生規劃
Marvelous.
說得真好
Dreams. Life plans.
夢想、人生規劃
Little buzzwords used to sell your dream home.
各種用來推銷夢想家園的流行話術
But dreams, plans, and even happiness
但是夢想、規劃，甚至是幸福
can all go up in flames in an instant.
都可以瞬間消失
So when you finally get ahold of them,
所以，如果終於能握在手中
you must never let them go.
就千萬別讓它們溜走
The time to buy
妳產生購買欲望的那個瞬間
is the moment you feel that desire to buy.
就是該出手的時機
It's not a realtor's job to push the client into a sale.
催促客人買賣並不是仲介該做的事
Gran.
奶奶
I don't need no high-rise.
我不需要摩天大樓的房子
And I definitely don't want you to sell your home in Akita.
我也絕不希望妳賣掉秋田的家
What?
什麼？
That place is full of memories we have together.
那裡充滿了我們共同的回憶
I absolutely treasure that place.
我把那裡視作珍寶
Just knowing that you're living your days in happiness and in good health
只要知道奶奶過得幸福健康
would be the biggest present of all for Minami.
對於美波小姐來說就是最好的禮物
Your old Gran can be a bit rash sometimes.
奶奶我啊，有時做事的確有些草率
I should have asked what you wanted.
我應該先問問美波妳想要什麼
Gran just got ahead of herself
但是奶奶卻自作主張
and started doing her own thing.
我自作主張了
Sorry, darling.
抱歉啊，我的寶貝
It's okay.
不會
I'm happy just knowing that you love me.
知道奶奶愛我，我很開心
Mr. Kamiki.
神木先生
Sorry to trouble you.
抱歉給你添麻煩了
Let's just forget about buying the high-rise.
買摩天大樓公寓的事就算了吧
I'm afraid it's too late.
恐怕已經來不及了
For you see, Mrs. Enomoto has already signed the contract.
你們看看，榎本婆婆已經簽了合約
If you renege on the contract now,
如果現在毀約
it will be at the buyer's discretion,
就屬於買方違約
and that eight-million-yen deposit will be forfeit.
八百萬訂金將不予退還
I won't get my money back?
我的錢拿不回來了嗎？
Well, shall I just buy it then?
不然我就買了吧？
Oh, no…
不會吧
Kamiki.
神木
The property you've foisted upon Mrs. Enomoto
你強行推銷給榎本婆婆的房子
is Heavenly Crest Yaoki, right?
是八起天廈吧？
People are claiming that one is defective.
很多人投訴說那裡有缺陷
Is this the defective one?
這就是有缺陷的那棟樓嗎？
Yeah, they say it's not even resistant to earthquakes.
對，聽說無法抗震
Mrs. Enomoto.
榎本婆婆
There are complaints that this property is not earthquake resistant.
有人投訴說這棟大樓不能抗震
Was this explained to you before you signed the contract?
你們簽合約之前 他向妳解釋清楚了嗎？
I knew I had a keen eye when it comes to men.
我看男人的眼光果然很準
I am a realtor.
我是不動產仲介
I won't allow real estate to be a source of unhappiness to those I care about.
我不允許我在乎的人 因為房子而不幸福
Kamiki.
神木
You knew this high-rise had a declining worth.
你明知這棟大樓正在貶值
You knew it was defective and yet you pushed it on an elderly woman.
也明知這裡有缺陷 卻仍強行推銷給一名老婦人
This is clearly a breach of your duty to disclose.
你顯然沒有盡到告知義務
Which means this contract is null and void, correct?
這表示這份合約無效，不是嗎？
Mrs. Enomoto.
榎本婆婆
I will make the appropriate arrangements to cancel your contract for you.
我會做好相關的安排，幫妳取消合約
Yes, please.
好的
Higashino, do we have any more of those sweets from that store?
東野，紅豆大福還有嗎？
What?
什麼？
Yes.
有
They're very good red bean mochi cakes.
那家的紅豆大福非常好吃
I see.
這樣啊
Would you like another cup of tea?
要不要再來杯茶？
Yes, please.
好的，謝謝
Tea readers would say this pattern is lucky.
茶葉算命師一定會說這是幸運的圖案
I'm sorry.
很抱歉
My contract with Hiroshi Watamura ended up being canceled.
我跟綿村博士的合約最終取消了
The five-million deposit you paid is now forfeit.
社長你墊付的五百萬訂金已無法退還
I will pay you back.
我會還給你
Don't bother.
不必了
You can earn it back.
賺回來就行
You're a realtor.
妳畢竟是不動產仲介
First place is mine.
第一名是我的
That's what I swore.
我發過誓
Here you go!
來了
Rice balls made with rice grown in Akita Prefecture.
這是用秋田米做的飯糰
Looks great! Thank you so much.
看起來很好吃，謝謝
We'll be bringing more food out.
還有其他食材，我們會陸續端上來
-Yes. -Okay, thank you.
-好的 -好，謝謝
You're really big on family, aren't you, Minami?
榎本小姐真是關心家人呢
I'm glad I got to catch a glimpse of such a rare and different side of you.
很高興看到妳如此難得 而且與平時不同的一面
-I was moved too. -What?
-我也一樣 -什麼？
I never knew you felt so strongly about me.
我真不知道 永瀨你對我的感情如此強烈
Do I?
有嗎？
You said you wouldn't let me be unhappy.
你說不允許我不幸福
I won't allow real estate to be a source of unhappiness to those I care about.
我不允許我在乎的人 因為房子而不幸福
I did.
那個啊
Mr. Nagase.
永瀨先生
You're her fiancé, right?
你就是美波的未婚夫吧？
That's--
這個嘛…
Actually--
其實…
That's right! They're absolutely smitten with each other.
沒錯，他們深愛著彼此
They're always coming here together.
他們總是一起來這裡
Anyone with eyes can see they're two peas in a pod.
明眼人都能看出來，他們是天生一對
And what do you like most about my dear Minami?
那你最喜歡我的寶貝美波哪點？
What do I like about her?
這個嘛…
Well, she's got great taste--
她很有品味
SHOJIKIMON
（正直食堂）
She's beautiful. She's kind.
人美心善
She's very stylish.
時髦亮麗
It's her meat and potato stew!
重點是她做的馬鈴薯燉肉
Meat and potato stew?
馬鈴薯燉肉？
She's a mean drunk and gets mad super easily.
她喝了酒說話就很刻薄 還非常容易生氣
She slaps me across the face and she rebukes any offer of physical touch!
她打過我一耳光 我提出想身體接觸，她就罵我
But I love her food, and her stew is sublime!
但是我愛她的廚藝 她做的燉肉無與倫比
And she's got a great bod, yeah!
而且她身材超好，沒錯
That's what I like about her!
我就是喜歡她這些
Did I take it too far?
我是不是說得太過分了？
Mr. Nagase! How could you say that? Of course it's too far!
永瀨前輩 你在胡說什麼？當然太過分了
You're the absolute worst.
真是混蛋
You sick, shameless pig!
你這無恥的變態
-No, stop! Watch out! -Just let it go!
-別這樣，小心 -快放開
-Minami! -Wait--
-美波 -等等
Minami!
美波
Your Gran's hunch is never wrong.
奶奶的直覺從沒錯過
I can tell
永瀨先生啊
that Mr. Nagase is obviously your soulmate.
絕對是美波命中註定的伴侶
What?
什麼？
Your grandpa
妳爺爺啊
used to love my meat and potato stew.
當初也愛我做的馬鈴薯燉肉
He adored it.
他超級喜歡
He loved it so much,
愛得不行
I couldn't help but fall for him.
我就情不自禁愛上他了
How lovely.
好可愛
Gran.
奶奶
Mr. Nagase.
永瀨先生
Thank you.
謝謝
Please…
美波…
take care
就交給你照顧了
of my dear little Minami.
拜託了
Who could that be this early in the morning?
這麼早會是誰啊？
I'm here!
我來了
What?
什麼？
I'll be living here from now on.
以後我就住在這裡了
You've been short-listed.
你是我的最終選擇
What?
什麼？
NEXT EPISODE
（下集預告）
I recommend Mr. Nagase, a realtor from Tosaka Real Estate.
我推薦登坂不動產的永瀨先生
He's famous for being brutally honest.
他是出了名的直言不諱
They say Mr. Nagase from Tosaka Real Estate is honest and reliable.
聽說登坂不動產的永瀨先生正直可靠
Full commission means my job's always on the line.
做自由仲介代表我隨時可能失業
Mr. Kurosu!
黑須先生
What's this?
什麽意思？
THE HONEST REALTOR 2 EP 7 - FORBIDDEN FRUIT
第7集：禁忌之果